<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 06:36:13 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_sport" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_sport"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Learning to ski on one leg</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://edition.cnn.com/2013/11/25/sport/matthias-lanzinger-skiing-recovery/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~3/baSnvkgV6Rs/index.html</link>
<description>There was no feeling in Matthias Lanzinger's leg when he regained consciousness in hospital after his skiing accident.&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~4/baSnvkgV6Rs" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2013 08:25:04 EST</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/11/25/sport/matthias-lanzinger-skiing-recovery/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>STORY HIGHLIGHTS
Matthias Lanzinger underwent leg amputation after crashing heavily on the World Cup circuit
Austrian skier gave up hope of skiing again but is now targeting medals at the Sochi Paralympics
A three-time medallist at this year's World Championships, Lanzinger is a strong contender
To this day, he still cannot watch back the accident - "I don't see any benefits at all"
(CNN) -- There was no feeling in Matthias Lanzinger's leg when he regained consciousness in hospital after his skiing accident.
As he blinked and opened his eyes, his first question to his wife, who was sitting at his bedside, was whether he would have to spend his life in a wheelchair.
"She said 'no you don't,'" Lanzinger told CNN. "'Everything is OK, you can get on with your life but they had to amputate your leg. Our life is going to go on."
He has absolutely no memory of the day five years ago when his life changed forever.
On Sunday March 2, 2008 he was competing in a World Cup Super-G race -- in Kvitfjell, Norway -- and crashed into a gate, falling down the mountainside, breaking his leg in the process.
"I just don't remember anything from the accident, it's nothing. I know until the gate and crashing, then nothing. I think it's good for me that way right now."
Amputee skier is ready for the Olympics
Sochi Olympic torch takes a spacewalk
The secret behind Ligety's success
Lanzinger was once the rising star of Austrian alpine skiing. A junior world champion, he had won the Europa Cup and picked up a podium finish in a World Cup Super-G in 2005.
But his horrific accident brutally halted his career's rising trajectory.
The resulting damage to his blood circulation in his leg meant the doctors had to amputate below the left knee -- had they not done so, he could have died.
"I know that maybe things could have been done differently," Lanzinger says wistfully.
"But what is the point of thinking about it? The fact is I can't change my amputation. When I think about it or I'm angry about it, it doesn't matter as the reality is that would not change a thing. So what's the point?
"The fact is I have an amputation and I look forward not back. I like to live life in a positive way."
Most immediately, he is looking forward to the 2014 Winter Olympics, his skiing career continuing but merely realigned after his life changing accident.
Where once he had aspired to compete in both Vancouver and Sochi alongside able bodied athletes, he will instead take part at the Paralympics in the Russian city, and he has modest ambitions.
Despite winning gold, silver and bronze at this season's World Championships, he has one, simple target.
"When I get to Sochi, a medal is the goal," he says, "and obviously gold would be nice. But more important than that is the way to Sochi.
"The years have been very tough, so this journey is still the most important.
"For me, the pleasure will just be to start in Sochi. If I could then get a medal -- even maybe a gold -- that would be the dream coming true. That is the reason why I did my comeback."
Lure of the slopes
U.S. Ski Team's big expectations
The main 40,000 all-seater Olympic Stadium, which has been nicknamed 'the fish' will host the opening and closing ceremonies.
The 12,000 Bolshoi Dome will host the highly-anticipated ice hockey final where the host nation will be hoping to challenge for the gold medal.
Located in the center of the Olympic Park, the Adler Arena will allow up to 8,000 spectators to watch the world's top speed skaters battle it out to claim sporting immortality.
The snowboarding and freestyle competitions will take place at the "Rosa Khutor" Extreme Park in the Mountain Cluster. The venue has already been used for World Cup events and is considered one of the top facilities in the world.
Russian ice dancer, World and Olympic champion, Tatiana Navka, performed with her partner at a ceremony celebrating the one year countdown to the Winter Games.
Australia's Heath Spence took part in a Men's Bobsleigh training run at the Sanki Sliding Centre, one of the 2014 Winter Olympics venues which is located at Rzhanaya Polyana, 60 kilometers northeast of Sochi.
Russia's President Vladimir Putin has taken a keen interest in the Games, visiting Sochi to ensure the project is finished in time. He visited the Olympic Village with Dmitry Chernyshenko, the CEO of the organizing committee.
With the Games set to start on February 7, the city faces a race against time to be ready. Workmen are up against tight deadlines with construction still to be completed.
The world's top ski jumpers will be hoping to fly through the air and onto the podium at the RusSki Gork center.
The view from 2,300 meters above sea level around Sochi. This photo was taken from Rosa Khutor resort, which will host the Alpine events.
The Fish
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
