<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Technology</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/TECH/index.html?eref=rss_tech</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 06:39:47 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Technology</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/TECH/index.html?eref=rss_tech</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_technology" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_technology"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>'Cyber Week' deals on phones, TVs, clothes</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2013/12/01/tech/web/cyber-monday-deals/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_technology/~3/yW6LsM9u7Mw/index.html</link>
<description>How eager are retailers to boost sales this holiday season? It's no longer enough for them to offer one special day of discounts to online shoppers -- they're stretching the deals out over an entire week.&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_technology/~4/yW6LsM9u7Mw" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 18:10:45 EST</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.cnn.com/2013/12/01/tech/web/cyber-monday-deals/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Cyber Monday deals on phones, TVs, clothes
By Brandon Griggs, CNN
December 2, 2013 -- Updated 1730 GMT (0130 HKT) | Filed under: Web
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
Retailers offering Cyber Monday deals of up to 50% on electronics and other items
Many websites now offer discounts throughout what they call "Cyber Week"
The term Cyber Monday was coined in 2005 by a retail lobbying group
(CNN) -- How eager are retailers to boost sales this holiday season? It's no longer enough for them to offer one special day of discounts to online shoppers -- they're stretching the deals out over an entire week.
While retailers are still trumpeting deals for this Monday after Thanksgiving, many such as Amazon, Target and Walmart are now promoting some version of "Cyber Week" and extending Web-only deals through next weekend. The online discounts apply to all types of items, from appliances to clothes to consumer electronics.
Walmart, for example, says it will offer 200 deals on its website each day through Friday, plus free shipping on all orders over $35. Not to be outdone, Amazon is promising new deals as often as every 10 minutes through Saturday, along with free shipping on "eligible orders" of $35 and over (it's not clear how they define "eligible.")
In fact, if you're not getting free shipping on your online purchases this week, you may want to shop elsewhere.
Navigating Black Friday and Cyber Monday
Clothing chains such as H&amp;M, Gap and Banana Republic also are offering storewide Cyber Monday discounts of 40%.
It's not always clear whether Cyber Monday discounts are much greater than what retailers offer online during other sale events. Also, supplies may be limited.
Here's a sampling of some online deals being advertised for Cyber Monday (and in many cases, the rest of the week):
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
