<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 06:36:13 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_sport" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_sport"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>McIlroy issues stress warning</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://edition.cnn.com/2013/11/27/sport/golf/rory-mcilroy-jonathan-trott-golf/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~3/B1eFI8Z-ODg/index.html</link>
<description>Two-time major winner Rory McIlory has warned that as the global interest in sport increases, so will players have to deal with the type of stress-related illness that prompted England cricket Jonathan Trott to pull out of the Ashes tour.&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~4/B1eFI8Z-ODg" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2013 09:11:44 EST</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/11/27/sport/golf/rory-mcilroy-jonathan-trott-golf/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Rory McIlroy issues stress-related illness warning
November 27, 2013 -- Updated 1457 GMT (2257 HKT)
Golfer Rory McIlroy expects more sports stars to succumb to stress-related illnesses.
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
Rory McIlroy says pressure in sports is leading to increase in stress-relates illnesses
England cricketer Jonathan Trott left the Ashes series this week citing a stress-related illness
McIlroy says it shows the mental toll sport can take on athletes
The Northern Irishman was speaking ahead of this week's Australian Open in Sydney
(CNN) -- Rory McIlroy is well versed to talk about the pressures the modern day sport star faces.
As a former world No.1 golfer and one half of a sporting super couple -- with tennis ace Caroline Wozniacki -- the Northern Irishman knows all about living in the full glare of the media spotlight.
So perhaps it is not surprising that the two-time major winner has warned that as the global interest in sport increases, so will players have to deal with the type of stress-related illness that prompted England cricketer Jonathan Trott to pull out of the Ashes tour.
Trott's decision to come home from Australia has prompted a debate about the relentless schedule of many sports and the support on offer to players if they succumb to mental health issues.
Garcia sorry for 'fried chicken' slur
Tiger Woods' nickname: Urkel?
"It's sad to see something like that happen and it just shows what a mental toll sport can take on you sometimes," McIlroy told reporters at Royal Sydney, ahead of this week's Australian Open as he talked about Trott's decision to leave the tour.
"Hopefully he gets home and spends some time with his family and recovers and can come back.
"As sport becomes so big and there's so much pressure and so much on the line, it's becoming more and more common that these sorts of stress-related illnesses are happening and it just shows how much of a mental toll it takes on you sometimes."
The rivalry between the England and Australia cricket teams is one of the oldest and fiercest in world sport, with the players often exchanging insults on the pitch -- a practice known as "sledging."
The sledging in the current series, which Australia lead 1-0 after winning the first Test match in Melbourne, saw Australia captain Michael Clarke fined for a barb aimed at England bowler James Anderson.
Read: Tears of joy for World Cup winner Day
"I think the sledging this year has probably been a bit worse than other years as well," said McIlroy. "It looks like they're just having a go at each other after every ball ... it would be really tough to take that for however long you're out there for.
Speculation abounds that sport's foremost golf and tennis love match have called it quits. Double major winner Rory McIlroy and former world No. 1 Caroline Wozniacki are staying tight lipped on their alleged break up, but when it comes to sport the path of true love rarely runs smooth. In this gallery, CNN looks at sporting couples who have aced their relationships and those who have seen their private lives hit the rough.
Jimmy Connors and Chris Evert had the world at their feet in 1974. The American lovebirds won both singles titles at Wimbledon and were engaged to be married, but by the time the grass-court grand slam came around in 1975 the wedding was off. Decades after splitting from the eight-time grand slam champion, Evert swapped the tennis court for the golf course...
Following the break up of her marriage to British tennis player John Lloyd in 1987 and a further divorce from Olympic skier Andy Mill in 2006, Evert tied the knot with Australian golf star Greg Norman in 2008. It would not be a case of third time lucky for Evert, however, as the pair separated in 2009 after an 18-month marriage.
Adam Scott followed in the footsteps of his hero Norman by sparking a golf and tennis romance of his own in 2010 with Serbia's Ana Ivanovic. The pair split in September of that year after both saw their form suffer, before unsuccessfully reuniting in 2011. Since the separation Scott has captured the first major title of his career and currently sits at No. 2 in the world rankings.
When Australian Lleyton Hewitt began a romance with fellow tennis ace Kim Clijsters in 2000, the former world No. 1's country took the Belgian to their hearts. She was dubbed "Aussie Kim" and it looked like they were set to live happily ever after with a wedding scheduled for February 2005. It was not to be and the pair split in October 2004, but Clijsters would still find her happy ending...
Now retired, Clijsters is happily married to former American basketball player Brian Lynch, with whom she has two children.
Like Clijsters, Maria Sharapova found love on the basketball court. The four-time grand slam winner got engaged to former Los Angeles Lakers star Sasha Vujacic, before ending her relationship with the Slovenian in 2012.
Radek Stepanek of the Czech Republic knows more than most about the trials and tribulations of a tennis fling. He was engaged to marry former world No. 1 Martina Hingis before the two called off their nuptials in 2007.
Undeterred, Stepanek started a second tennis fling with compatriot Nicole Vaidisova and the couple married in June 2010, but announced earlier this year they have filed for divorce. If Stepanek feels disillusioned with the idea of a tennis romance, there is one golden couple who he can take heart from...
Tennis super stars Andre Agassi and Steffi Graf are living proof that sporting couples can go the distance. The former world No. 1s married in 2001 and have two children together.
'Wozilroy' split?
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
