<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 06:36:13 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_sport" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_sport"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Stadium deaths hit Brazil</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://edition.cnn.com/2013/11/27/world/americas/brazil-stadium-accident/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~3/Ds1-8PQtGCs/index.html</link>
<description>A falling crane struck a stadium under construction in Sao Paulo, Brazil, on Wednesday, killing several people, CNN affiliate Globo TV reported, citing the local fire department.&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~4/Ds1-8PQtGCs" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 13:33:04 EST</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/11/27/world/americas/brazil-stadium-accident/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Brazil hit by World Cup stadium deaths
By Mariano Castillo, CNN
November 28, 2013 -- Updated 0053 GMT (0853 HKT)
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
NEW: State media: 30% of the stadium will be closed off as authorities investigate
A crane hoisting a piece of roofing collapsed at the Arena Corinthians
Two workers were killed
The accident comes as Brazil tries to meet a deadline for completing its stadiums
(CNN) -- A construction accident at the site of the Brazilian stadium that will host the opening match of the World Cup killed two workers, Sao Paulo fire officials said Wednesday.
Officials initially said there were three victims, but the fire department amended the death toll on its Twitter account.
The Arena Corinthians is one of the venues that will host World Cup matches in 2014.
A crane was hoisting a part of the metal roof when it collapsed, causing the piece to fall, partially damaging the building, according to a statement released by the construction company, Odebrecht Infrastructure.
It was a procedure that had been carried out many times at the construction site without incident, including the installation a week ago of a piece of roof of the same proportions, the company said.
The stadium is to be the home of Sport Club Corinthians Paulista. The club's directors issued a statement expressing sadness over the incident.
The construction company identified the victims as Fabio Luiz Pereira, 42, and Ronaldo Oliveira dos Santos, 44.
The Arena Castelao is the first stadium ready for the eight-nation Confederations Cup in June 2013. The competition, which is a dress rehearsal for the the 2014 World Cup, will bring together four former world champions.
View of the Governador Magalhaes Pinto stadium during renovation works, in Belo Horizonte. The stadium will host both the Brazil 2013 FIFA Confederations Cup and the Brazil 2014 FIFA World Cup.
Picture of the famed Maracana football stadium in Rio de Janeiro as renovation works for the 2014 World Cup -- including the construction of a roof -- gets under way. The Maracana is classified as a historic monument so the facade will be maintained but a roof will be added to the five-storey oval stadium.
Picture taken during the refurbishment works held at the Mario Filho 'Maracana' stadium in Rio de Janeiro.
A huge inflatable Fuleco, the mascot of the Brazil 2014 FIFA World Cup, stands by the Maracana stadium in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, on January 15, 2013.
A worker swings a hammer inside 'Arena Fonte Nova' stadium in Salvador de Bahia, Brazil on December 6, 2012 before next June's eight-nation Confederations Cup.
A construction worker at the site of the Itaquerao football stadium which will host the opening football matches of the FIFA World Cup 2014 in Sao Paulo, Brazil.
Brasilia's National Stadium under construction on December 13, 2012. The National Stadium will receive the first match of the eight-nation Confederations Cup matches on June 2013.
A panel marks the exact place of the kick off for the next FIFA World Cup 2014.
Former Brazilian footballer Ronaldo attends a press conference on November 29, 2012 in Sao Paulo, Brazil.
The trophy of the FIFA World Cup 2014, brought to Brazil by former Brazilian football player Cafu from the FIFA headqueaters in Switzerland, is displayed at Morumbi shopping center in Sao Paulo, Brazil, on September 22, 2012.
Police commandos from an anti-kidnapping unit, arrest and control a group of 'terrorists' during a drill at the Tom Jobim International Airport in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, on January 13, 2012.
People chant slogans during a protest against the demolition of the Celio de Barros track and field stadium in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil on January 13, 2013. The stadium needs to be demolished to carry out the Maracana stadium construction plans ahead of the 2013 FIFA Confederations Cup, 2014 FIFA World Cup and 2016 Olympic games.
The Rio 2016 Olympics logo is seen on a wall of the future Olympic Park in construction in Barra de Tijuca, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil on November 20, 2012.
Carlos Arthur Nuzman (left), Brazilian Olympic Committee President and Rio 2016 Olympics Committee President, shakes hands with London 2012 Chief Executive Paul Deighton after delivering the IOC debriefing of the London 2012 Olympic Games for the foreign press in Barra de Tijuca, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.
People hold a huge banner during a demonstration demanding that Brazilian President Dilma Roussef veto a bill that would redistribute oil royalties in favor of non-oil producing states.
The construction site of the future Olympic village for the Rio 2016 Olympic games in Barra de Tijuca, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil on November 20, 2012, Brazil.
Journalists are shown a virtual tour of the city organized by the Rio 2016 Committee on November 19, 2012 in Rio De Janeiro, Brazil.
Brazil prepares for World Cup and Olympics
Brazil prepares for World Cup and Olympics
Brazil prepares for World Cup and Olympics
Brazil prepares for World Cup and Olympics
Brazil prepares for World Cup and Olympics
Brazil prepares for World Cup and Olympics
Brazil prepares for World Cup and Olympics
Brazil prepares for World Cup and Olympics
Brazil prepares for World Cup and Olympics
Brazil prepares for World Cup and Olympics
Brazil prepares for World Cup and Olympics
Brazil prepares for World Cup and Olympics
Brazil prepares for World Cup and Olympics
Brazil prepares for World Cup and Olympics
Brazil prepares for World Cup and Olympics
Brazil prepares for World Cup and Olympics
Brazil prepares for World Cup and Olympics
Brazil prepares for World Cup and Olympics
HIDE CAPTION
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
