<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 06:36:13 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_sport" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_sport"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Milan legends in Iran</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://edition.cnn.com/2013/11/28/sport/football/ac-milan-iran-persepolis-football/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~3/CPdNLxEdIfA/index.html</link>
<description>As Iran's relations with the Western world seem to be thawing following a historic U.S. agreement over its nuclear production, sport is also doing its part to bring Tehran in from the cold.&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~4/CPdNLxEdIfA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 17:15:51 EST</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/11/28/sport/football/ac-milan-iran-persepolis-football/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>AC Milan legends give Iranian soccer fans a boost
November 28, 2013 -- Updated 1933 GMT (0333 HKT)
Iranian supporters of AC Milan welcome former players of the Italian soccer club for a charity match at Tehran's Azadi stadium.
The Milan Glorie team took on a side made up of former Persepolis FC players in the fundraiser, which also celebrated the career of former Iran captain Mehdi Mahdavikia.
The 36-year-old played more than 100 times for his country and spent eight years at German club Hamburg. He is seen (right) here with Gennaro Gattuso, who won the World Cup with Italy in 2006 and the European Champions League twice with Milan.
The star-studded Milan side included legendary defender Paolo Maldini, pictured center with teammate Stefano Eranio and Persepolis' Pejman Jamshidi (right). Maldini spent his entire career at Milan before retiring at the age of 41 in 2009.
The 52-year-old Daniele Massaro -- part of Italy's 1982 World Cup-winning squad -- challenges former Iran international Pejman Jamshidi, who has become the subject of a TV show in his home country since retiring.
Dario Simic, who played at three World Cups for Croatia, tries to block a shot by Behnam Abolghasempour -- who has moved into coaching since retiring and is now an assistant at Persepolis.
Former Italy defender Pietro Vierchowod played more than 550 games in Serie A, but had only a brief spell at Milan late in his career. The 54-year-old here contests a header with Payan Rafat, who had two spells with Persepolis -- one of Asia's most popular clubs -- before becoming a coach.
HIDE CAPTION
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
Iranian soccer fans welcome AC Milan to Tehran for charity match against Persepolis
The game is part of a collaboration between the two clubs, giants in Europe and Asia
Persepolis hoping to learn from Milan's highly-regarded youth academy
Milan's team of former stars beat their counterparts 3-1 in front of 65,000 crowd
(CNN) -- As Iran's relations with the Western world seem to be thawing following a historic U.S. agreement over its nuclear production, sport is also doing its part to bring Tehran in from the cold.
AC Milan, the world's most successful soccer club in terms of trophies won, sent a team stacked full of its former stars to take part in a charity match against counterparts from Persepolis FC.
Thursday's game, watched by 65,000 fans in Persepolis' Azadi Stadium, was won 3-1 by the seven-time European champion.
Tweets by @CNNFC
It is part of a collaboration that began at the end of last year when Persepolis president Mohammad Rouyanian visited Italy to meet with Milan chief executive and V.P. Adriano Galliani.
Milan's website reports that the "Rossoneri" ("black and reds") will be sharing knowledge of the club's successful youth academy with Persepolis -- which is Iran's most successful team and one of the most popular in Asia.
"Mohammad Rouyanian expressed his admiration for the way that the club and its proprietor made Milan the most decorated in the world," the website said. "The desire to create and develop a form of collaboration between the two clubs came naturally.
"Collaboration is already underway that will see the Milan Academy help to export and replicate the Milan Model with Persepolis, which celebrates its 50-year anniversary this year."
Legendary defender Paolo Maldini headed a star-studded Milan lineup at the 100,000-capacity Azadi Stadium for a match that marked the last Persepolis appearance for former Iran captain Mehdi Mahdavikia.
Mahdavikia, 36, retired this year following a distinguished career in which he appeared at two World Cups -- representing his country 111 times in all -- and spent eight seasons with German club Hamburg.
The Milan team also included another of Italy's defensive greats, Franco Baresi, and his fellow World Cup winner Gennaro Gattuso.
Its goals came from Daniele Massaro -- part of Italy's 1982 World Cup-winning squad -- Christian Lantignotti and Stefano Eranio, while Alireza Emamifar scored for Persepolis.
"Thank you to @acmilan glorie for coming to Iran and putting a smile on the Iranian AC Milan fans :)" one supporter wrote on Twitter.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
