<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 06:36:13 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_sport" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_sport"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Motorsport: Death at Simoncelli event </title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://edition.cnn.com/2013/11/30/sport/motorsport/motocycling-romboni-death/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~3/YlTovjsJH4I/index.html</link>
<description>Former Italian motorcycle racer Doriano Romboni has been killed in an accident at an event marking the memory of late MotoGP rider Marco Simoncelli.&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~4/YlTovjsJH4I" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 16:03:30 EST</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/11/30/sport/motorsport/motocycling-romboni-death/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Former Italian racer Doriano Romboni killed at Simoncelli memorial event
November 30, 2013 -- Updated 2100 GMT (0500 HKT)
Italy's Dariano Romboni in a picture taken prior to the 1996 Malaysian Grand Prix.
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
Former Italian 500cc racer dies following accident at Marco Simoncelli tribute event
Doriano Romboni fatally injured after being struck by another motorcycle
Romboni airlifted to hospital but pronounced dead shortly after arrival
(CNN) -- Former Italian motorcycle racer Doriano Romboni has been killed in an accident at an event marking the memory of late MotoGP rider Marco Simoncelli.
Romboni, 44, was struck by another motorcycle during a training session for the second annual "Sic Supermoto Day" at Italy's Latina circuit, 70 kilometers south east of the capital Rome.
Following the incident, Romboni was airlifted to hospital but died shortly after arrival, Italian News Agency ANSA reported.
The fatal accident has echoes of the way his compatriot Simoncelli died. The 24-year-old was killed following a collision with American rider Colin Edwards and Italy's Valentino Rossi during the Malaysian Grand Prix in October 2011.
Romboni was a six-time winner in 125cc and 250cc races and competed in the 500cc class (the forerunner to MotoGP) from 1996-1998 with his best finish coming at the 1997 Dutch TT at Assen where he finished third for the Aprilia team.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
