<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 06:36:13 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_sport" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_sport"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Giggs: Fit, 40 and still firing</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://edition.cnn.com/2013/11/29/sport/football/ryan-giggs-40-manchester-united-football/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~3/mQuJRAiFKfI/index.html</link>
<description>As he celebrates his 40th birthday, just what is the secret to Ryan Giggs' longevity?&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~4/mQuJRAiFKfI" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2013 11:03:36 EST</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/11/29/sport/football/ryan-giggs-40-manchester-united-football/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>&gt;&gt;
David Moyes: Alex Ferguson's successor
"Ryan is obviously a different player now compared to when he broke through as a 17-year-old winger," Henning Berg, who played alongside Giggs at United between 1997 and 2000, told the club's official website.
"But that says a lot about how football has developed in terms of sports science to make sure that players still have enough power and energy to play the physical part of the game."
Even accounting for advances in sports science, Giggs' ability to remain effective at the top level as he enters his fifth decade is still exceptional.
Read: Belounis back in France after Qatar "nightmare"
Italian defensive stalwart Paolo Maldini, a picture of durability and the rock of a successful AC Milan defense for 24 years, called time on his own glittering career at Giggs' age.
Brazilian striker Romario retired in 2008 aged 42, before making a one-game comeback in 2009, saying he was unable to regulate his body weight while not playing regularly.
It is Giggs' ability to remain in peak physical condition which sets him apart from other aged soccer stars.
Few players could have controlled a top-level match the way Giggs did this week, orchestrating United's 5-0 demolition of Bayer Leverkusen in a Champions League group match.
United manager David Moyes, who took over from Ferguson at Old Trafford, is still a keen admirer of Giggs' talents.
The Scot highlighted Giggs as the perfect role model for any young player looking for a long, successful career in the sport.
"People mention his age but all you should mention is his football ability," Moyes, who has appointed Giggs as a player/coach, told a press conference.
"He's an unbelievable footballer. All round he is a wonderful player and I am really fortunate to be working with him.
Aerial view of the Christ the Redeemer statue atop Corcovado Hill and the Maracana stadium in Rio de Janeiro, BrazIl. The famous arena will host the World Cup final on July 13 at an tournament in which 32 teams will compete.
Ask many Brazilians who is the greatest footballer of all time and their answer will be simple: "Pele." The striker won three World Cups with Brazil between 1958 and 1970 and is his country's leading goalscorer with 77 goals from 92 caps.
The Brazil team of 1970, which beat Italy 4-1 in the World Cup final in Mexico, is widely regarded as the greatest of all time. Pele, a three-time World Cup winner is seen here leaping on his teammates.
Neymar will be the man which the Brazilian public will look to for inspiration at the 2014 World Cup. The Barcelona striker starred in the country's Confederations Cup success in July 2013
Despite winning the Champions League and Spanish title with Barcelona, Argentina's Lionel Messi has yet to taste success on the international stage.
Cristiano Ronaldo's hat-trick fired Portugal into the 2014 World Cup after his side defeated Sweden in the playoffs. Ronaldo is the country's joint-top scorer with Pauleta on 47 goals.
Luis Suarez played a key role in Uruguay's run to the World Cup. The Liverpool striker was part of the squad which reached the semifinals in South Africa and scored 11 goals in qualifying.
Sweden's forward Zlatan Ibrahimovic will have to watch the tournament at home -- that's if he's even interested. He told reporters: "A World Cup without me is nothing to watch so it is not worthwhile to wait for the World Cup."
Spain is hoping to become the third country to retain the World Cup. Italy won the tournament in 1934 and 1938, while Brazil triumphed in 1958 and 1962. Andres Iniesta scored the winning goal in the 2010 final.
Falcao will be one of the players to watch at the tournament with the Monaco striker considered to be one of the most lethal finishers in the game. Falcao scored nine goals in qualifying while his side netted 25 overall.
Belgium is one of the teams fancied to do well in Brazil. The Belgians reached the semifinals in 1986 and are expected to challenge in the later stages this time around thanks to a crop of outstanding young players.
Cameroon is the lowest ranked team in the tournament. The Indomitable Lions are the 59th best team in the world according to FIFA. It reached the quarterfinals in 1990 where it was beaten by England.
Miroslav Klose, 35, looks set to feature in a fourth World Cup after helping Germany cruise through qualifying. Klose is the country's joint-top scorer on 68 goals alongside Gerd Muller.
Bosnian football fans will flock to Brazil after their football team qualified for the World Cup for the very first time. Bosnia finished top of its group and clinched its place at the tournament courtesy of a 1-0 win over Lithuania.
Three times the Netherlands has reached the final -- and three times it has been beaten. In 1974 it lost out to West Germany before Argentina triumphed four years later. Four years ago it was beaten 1-0 by Spain.
Tim Cahill needs one more goal to become Australia's top scorer. He currently has 29, leaving him level with Damian Mori.
France became the first European team to overturn a two-goal deficit in a World Cup playoff to secure its place in Brazil. Liverpool defender Mamadou Sakho scored twice as France defeated Ukraine 3-0 on the night, 3-2 on aggregate.
Spain will be one of the favorites to win the tournament but no European side has ever won the competition outside its own continent.
Setting the World Cup stage
'The greatest'
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
