<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Business</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/BUSINESS/index.html?eref=rss_business</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 09:33:11 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Business</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/BUSINESS/index.html?eref=rss_business</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_business" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_business"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Secrets of art copycats</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://edition.cnn.com/2013/11/29/world/europe/a-stroke-of-genius-copyists/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_business/~3/yiRIgvTeZtk/index.html</link>
<description>On any given day at the Louvre there will be dozens of people copying the great masterpieces. Who are the copyists and why do they do it?&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_business/~4/yiRIgvTeZtk" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2013 07:20:11 EST</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/11/29/world/europe/a-stroke-of-genius-copyists/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>A stroke of genius: Meet the copyists recreating the Louvre's masterpieces
From Sheena McKenzie, for CNN, and Nick Glass, CNN
December 2, 2013 -- Updated 1249 GMT (2049 HKT)
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
Who are the Louvre's copyists and why do they do it?
Since 1700s, artists have copied the gallery's masterpieces
Famous copyists included Pablo Picasso and Paul Cezanne
Today, just 150 copyists allowed, one year waiting list
Editor's note: CNN takes you "Inside the Louvre," building an intimate portrait of a museum like no other. From the handler who looks after the Mona Lisa's famous smile, to the new director, host Nick Glass meets the people at the heart of Paris' most renowned institution. Watch the 30-minute special show from Dec 2-4.
(CNN) -- Sigrid Avrillier might be a 65-year-old woman living in Paris, but for four hours each day she is transformed into the legendary Renaissance painter, Peter Paul Rubens.
You wouldn't know it to look at her -- a former physics teacher with mousey brown hair and a cheeky gap-toothed smile. But over the last few months Avrillier has come to know Rubens intimately, recreating his every brush stroke, his every color choice.
Behind the scenes of the Louvre
Restoring the Mona Lisa
CNN goes inside Paris' Louvre Museum
"I live with him," she says. "I become him."
Avrillier is a copyist. And if you wander around the grand rooms of Paris' Louvre gallery, you'll see dozens of people just like her with their easels pitched in front of a masterpiece, paintbrush at the ready.
Curious children scamper up to them, doing a double-take between the painting on the wall and the version being created before their eyes: "What are you doing?" they ask.
The copyists are recreating some of the most famous paintings in the world, in a remarkable tradition dating back to when the museum first opened in 1793.
Read: Mona Lisa -- The theft that created a legend
Grand tradition
It's a tradition that continues today -- albeit it, in a far more regimented fashion. Just 150 copyists are allowed in the Louvre, with a one-year waiting list for the privilege.
Each canvas is signed, dated, and stamped three times before even a drop of paint hits it. And even then, it must not be the same size as the original or include the artist's signature.
Five-days-a-week, from 9.30am to 1.30pm, copyists stream into the most popular museum on the planet , using one of the easels and stools provided.
There is one easel however, which never leaves the office -- the very same one renowned post-impressionist painter Paul Cezanne used 150 years ago.
Mastering the masters
Indeed, Cezanne, who would often copy the great masters, once famously said: "The Louvre is the book from which we learn to read."
He wasn't alone. Pablo Picasso also painted a fantastical version of Eugene Delacroix's "Women of Algiers."
"That bastard," Picasso reportedly said of Delacroix. "He's really good!"
Read: Europe's greatest museum treasures
Officials crowd around the Mona Lisa upon her return to the Louvre in January 1914. Why such a fuss? She'd been missing for over two years.
Until she was stolen in 1911, the Mona Lisa was not necessarily the most famous painting in the world. When Italian handyman Vincenzo Peruggia stole Leonardo da Vinci's masterpiece, it made international headlines and was catapulted to stardom.
Today, the 16th century artwork is the most recognizable painting on the planet, helping to attract over 9.7 million visitors to the Louvre last year. The mysterious muse has been immortalized in everything from Andy Warhol's pop art to Dan Brown's bestselling novel, "The Da Vinci Code."
"It's what people describe as invisible masterpieces -- people know of them but they may have never seen them. They're more interested in saying that they've seen them, rather than actually looking at them," said art history professor Noah Charney.
Pretty as a picture
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
