<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 10:34:11 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Beckham enters hotel business</title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/12/01/travel/david-beckham-enters-hotel-game/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/12/01/travel/david-beckham-enters-hotel-game/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>Global resort developer Las Vegas Sands (LVS) and Beckham Ventures just announced a partnership that will have the retired footballer (or soccer player, depending on your birth certificate) team up with the brand's integrated resort properties in Macao and Singapore.</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 20:11:31 EST</pubDate>
<ExtractedText>David Beckham, hotel magnate? The retired footballer teams up with major casino resort brand
By Karla Cripps, CNN
December 2, 2013 -- Updated 1330 GMT (2130 HKT)
You can't deny he looks good in a suit. David Beckham -- future hotelier -- watches Manny Pacquiao fight Brandon Rios during the "Clash in Cotai" at the Venetian Macao on November 24.
"Now that I've conquered bodywear, perhaps it's time to make my move into hotels," David Beckham might be thinking.
The Las Vegas Sands group spent $2.4 billion to build its Macau replica of the Las Vegas original. There's even Grand Canal Shoppes complete with gondolas, on which gondoliers serenade guests.
The Venetian isn't just the biggest casino in Macau. It lays claims to having the world's largest casino floor -- almost 540,000 square feet of gaming space.
With 2,560 rooms and more than 10,000 staff, the $5.5 billion Marina Bay Sands has become Singapore's most famous landmark since opening in 2010 thanks to the boat-shaped rooftop that connects its three towers and dominates the skyline. Already home to several celebrity chef restaurants, the Beckham brand will be right at home here.
Game on! A general view of the Marina Bay Sands casino, which opened in 2010. Singapore's two casinos generated about $5.85 billion in gambling revenue in 2012, putting it in behind Vegas for third in the world gaming revenue rankings.
HIDE CAPTION
Beckham hits the 'Clash in Cotai'
David Beckham for H&amp;M
David Beckham enters hotel game
Venetian Macau
&gt;&gt;
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
Las Vegas Sands and Beckham Ventures partnership will see the retired footballer work with brands in Macau and Singapore
Partnership based around the development of dining, retail and leisure concepts
In the U.S., Beckham looking to bring a new Major League Soccer franchise to Miami
(CNN) -- When David Beckham was spotted in the Macau crowd at last weekend's Manny Pacquio vs. Brandon Rio fight -- his handsome mug given a nice share of screen time -- most of us assumed he was there just as a boxing fan.
Turns out there was a little deal in the works as well.
Global resort developer Las Vegas Sands (LVS) and Beckham Ventures just announced a partnership that will have the retired footballer team up with the brand's integrated resort properties in Macao and Singapore.
David Beckham, hotelier? Has a nice ring to it. And it's likely the former England captain knows a thing or two about sheet thread counts given the amount of time he's logged on the road.
But sadly, as much as many of us would love to stay in a Beckham-designed suite, it seems his expertise will be put to use in other areas.
Details on specific projects weren't released but according to LVS the partnership will be based around the development of "dining, retail and leisure concepts" at Sands China properties in Macao and Marina Bay Sands in Singapore.
More: 10 things to know before visiting Macau
"We have billions of dollars invested in our own global, iconic brands and we clearly understand the importance of growing and sustaining those brands over time," said Michael Leven, president and chief operating officer of Las Vegas Sands Corp, in a statement.
"Now that I've conquered bodywear, perhaps it's time to make my move into hotels."
"The odds are extremely high that a partnership with David Beckham will help us further those efforts and provide David with the same benefit. We are very excited about the partnership and we fully expect it to grow in the years to come, especially as we aggressively explore opportunities to further expand our presence in Asia."
That's corporate speak for "David Beckham's name brings in big bucks."
"The Sands team has created amazing resorts in Singapore and Macau," said Beckham in a statement.
"The scale, vision and caliber in all that they do is impressive. I am very excited to be working with them to develop a range of new business ideas in a part of the world that I love spending time in and is full of optimism and growth."
What's Becks getting himself into?
Macau has 33 casinos -- with more on the way -- run by six casino operators: SJM Holdings (Stanley Ho), Wynn Macau, Sands China, Galaxy Entertainment Group, MGM China Holdings and Melco Crown Entertainment.
According to a recent report in Bloomberg , gambling revenue in the Chinese city rose 18% to 297.1 billion patacas ($37.2 billion) in the first 10 months of this year, close to the $38 billion revenue the city raked in for the whole of 2012. That's six times more than the Las Vegas Strip earned.
Leading the way is the Sands' Venetian property. With almost 540,000 square feet of gaming space, it has the largest casino floor in the world. The Las Vegas Sands group spent $2.4 billion to build this replica of the Las Vegas original.
In Singapore, there are only two casinos -- Las Vegas Sands Corp.'s Marina Bay Sands and Genting Singapore PLC's Resorts World Sentosa. They generated about $5.85 billion in gambling revenue in 2012, putting Singapore behind Vegas for third in the world gaming revenue rankings.
With 2,560 rooms and more than 10,000 staff, the $5.5 billion Marina Bay Sands has become Singapore's most famous landmark since opening in 2010 thanks to the boat-shaped rooftop that connects its three towers and dominates the skyline.
More: Macau's best casinos: Where to gamble, where to let loose
Beckham's Miami dreams
David Beckham waves after his team Paris St. Germain played Brest in his final home match in Paris on Saturday, May 18. Beckham signed on with the team just a few months ago, and now he is retiring. Click through for a look back at Beckham through the years.
Beckham poses with Paris Saint-Germain President Nasser Al-Khelaifi, left, and PSG sports director Leonardo during a press conference announcing his new gig in January 2013.
Beckham makes his England debut at a World Cup Europe Qualifying Round Group 2 match against Moldova in 1996.
Beckham celebrates his goal in the 1998 World Cup Finals versus Colombia in 1998.
Becks as a member of Manchester United cools down during the FA Charity Shield match against Arsenal at Wembley Stadium in London in 1998.
At the 1998 World Cup in France, in a second-round match against Argentina, Beckham was sent off for kicking out at Diego Simeone. England lost the match on penalties and was eliminated, with Beckham becoming a hate figure for some fans.
Beckham poses after a press conference in Awaji-shima Island, Japan, in 2002.
Beckham poses with Beyonce, left, and Jennifer Lopez during a presentation of the new Pepsi "Samourai" in Madrid in 2004.
Becks waves after a la Liga match between Real Madrid and Deportivo La Coruna in Madrid in 2007.
The midfielder celebrates with his sons in 2007 after Real Madrid won the Spanish League title by beating Mallorca.
Beckham makes an appearance to promote his fragrance "David Beckham Intimately Night" in Sydney in 2007.
Beckham reveals his new No. 32 Adidas jersey as part of an announcement of the start of his loan move to AC Milan from the Los Angeles Galaxy in 2008.
Beckham controls the ball during the 2010 FIFA World Cup qualifier of European Group 6.
Beckham unveils the new Emporio Armani underwear ad campaign for the fall/winter of 2009-2010.
Beckham, No. 23 of the Los Angeles Galaxy soccer team, walks toward the line judge to have a chat during Game 1 of the MLS Western Conference Semifinals against Chivas USA in 2009.
Becks arrives at Sydney International Airport in 2010.
David and Victoria Beckham arrive at the wedding of Prince William and Kate Middleton at Westminster Abbey in 2011.
The Beckhams attend the Vanity Fair Oscar Party in West Hollywood, California, in 2012.
Beckham celebrated his second MLS Cup success with the Los Angeles Galaxy in December 2012, when he decided to leave with a year left on his contract as he sought one final career challenge in Europe.
Beckham passes under Tower Bridge in a speedboat which carries the Olympic Torch and its torchbearer in 2012.
Beckham acts as England's captain during the 2004 European Nations Championship football match against Croatia in Lisbon, Portugal.
David Beckham through the years
David Beckham through the years
Making his debut
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
