<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 10:34:11 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Onboard the USS George Washington</title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/11/30/world/asia/asia-us-navy-power/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/11/30/world/asia/asia-us-navy-power/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>As tensions ratchet up in East Asia, CNN goes on exercise with the USS George Washington -- the flagship aircraft carrier of the Japanese-based 7th Fleet.</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 01:48:49 EST</pubDate>
<ExtractedText>Speed: More than 30 knots
Length of Flight Deck: 1,092 feet
Width of Flight Deck: 275 feet
Height (keel to mast): 244 feet
Flight Deck Area: 4.5 acres
Displacement: 97,000 tons
"The maritime domain in general has got more complex, with the undersea domain a huge part of that with more sophisticated submarines and the emergence of long-endurance, unmanned or remotely operated vehicles," he said.
"You see it just in oceanographic capabilities. Frankly the way countries globally are using technology in the undersea domain is going to make it a very interesting operational space. So the traditional 'hey I've got a submarine and I get to play here,' mindset I think is naïve. You're going to have to bring a lot more capability into that operating space to ensure you stay dominant -- economically as well as militarily.
"As to the asymmetric threats, the one thing that cannot be counted out is the ability of terrorists to use the maritime domain. It's not just in close, such as we saw when the USS Cole was attacked (in port in Yemen in 200), all of a sudden it's threats to commercial shipping and 'choke' points.
"Major commercial carriers such as Maersk all have immediate response actions already in place in case the Singapore Strait is cut off or they can't use a port due to a weapon of mass destruction."
He said this was a major "economic game changer" when you consider the cost of shutting down major waterways or ports due to terrorist threats. "So a lot more thinking has to be done" about how to counter these kind of challenges, he added.
The nature of the joint exercises with Japanese forces -- known as AnnualEx 2013 and involving more than 23 ships and 20,000 servicemen and women -- in part acknowledges this, he said, with the fleet deployed on a variety of "graduate level" missions, from anti-submarine warfare, to defending against hostile incursions against territory.
Awesome power
Standing on the flight deck of the USS George Washington, the noise of combat jets as they take off and land just meters away generates an incredible vibration that almost lifts you from your feet -- awesome power that is very difficult not to be impressed by whether you're a journalist or a foreign power.
But Thomas seems anything but a man on the verge of using this immense force in anger -- especially against any perceived Chinese threat.
U.S. 'advising' airlines to 'comply' over disputed zone
He said the China's People's Liberation Army Navy was becoming a highly professional organization and improving the way they operate and communicate -- and far from being one prone to making rash moves.
"I can tell just by our bridge-to-bridge communications that they're getting better at it. They've got a three-ship surface action group coming back from South America. They've been operating in the Gulf of Aden doing counter-piracy operations. And they're operating here in the Western Pacific all at the same time. Two years ago it was a big deal if they were able to conduct an exercise in the Philippines Sea for a week, now it's routine."
Japan balks at China's territory claim
Japan, China in dispute over claimed space
U.S. defies China's newly claimed airspace
From carrier to 'lily pad'
Thomas was also keen to expand on the U.S. Navy's diversity of operations, most notably their recent humanitarian mission in the Philippines after Super Typhoon Haiyan had flattened much of the eastern parts of the country.
Within 48 hours, the carrier and nine other surface vessels had left Hong Kong and arrived in the Philippines Sea to begin carrying our relief operations.
Combat aircraft were deliberately flown off the carrier to make room for more helicopters able to deliver badly needed assistance to areas made inaccessible by the typhoon and the subsequent storm surge. Thomas said in many cases, the U.S. Seahawk helicopters were "first responders" able to relay back previously unknown information about local conditions and the extent of the disaster.
"We transitioned (the carrier) into a vertical lift lily pad for the delivery of food and water supplies," he said.
Critics may point to this being an example of Washington adopting a "soft power" approach politically in the region at a time when its influence is being challenged by China, though there was little doubting the pride expressed by many of the carrier's highly-trained and motivated crew in performing such a role in the Leyte Gulf.
Relief effort boosts U.S. soft power in Asia region
But does serving as a deterrent or performing aid missions with hugely expensive weapons of war justify the vast cost of maintaining such an arsenal?
The use of unmanned drones in other theaters illustrates that massed armies with boots on the ground, tanks and artillery are not necessarily the most effective way of dealing with terrorism or insurgencies with a minimal cost in terms of deaths to combatants.
With military expansion seemingly inextricably linked to economic progress, and the exponential growth of armed forces fueled by territorial disputes in the Asia-Pacific region, the large-scale presence of this carrier strike group seems unlikely to change, though the scope of its missions will adapt to meet the increasing diversity of challenges -- both hard and soft.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
