<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 10:10:45 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_entertainment" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_entertainment"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Brown out of rehab for 'acting violently' </title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2013/11/20/showbiz/chris-brown-rehab/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~3/_fPra-Jkm9U/index.html</link>
<description>Chris Brown was booted from a rehab facility this month after smashing his mother's car window during a family session, his probation officer reported Wednesday.&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~4/_fPra-Jkm9U" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 10:02:05 EST</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.cnn.com/2013/11/20/showbiz/chris-brown-rehab/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Chris Brown, kicked out of rehab for 'acting violently,' ordered to new facility
By Alan Duke, CNN
November 21, 2013 -- Updated 1024 GMT (1824 HKT)
Singer Chris Brown has managed to intrigue -- and infuriate -- the public since he first burst onto the scene in 2005. Here's a look at his life and career.
Brown poses with his award for Best New Artist at the Soul Train Music Awards in March 2006. That year, Brown also won male artist of the year, new artist of the year and artist of the year at the Billboard Music Awards.
Brown, left, appeared with "Scandal" star Columbus Short in the 2007 film "Stomp the Yard."
Brown started dating fellow singer Rihanna in 2008, and the pair appeared to be the perfect match. Here, they dance the night away in December of that year. A few months later, Brown was charged with assaulting her on the eve of the Grammy Awards.
In April 2009, Brown pleads not guilty to felony charges of assault and making threats related to the Rihanna incident.
Rihanna and attorney Donald Etra appear at a preliminary hearing in June 2009. The hearing was to determine if Brown would stand trial for allegedly attacking Rihanna during an argument in a rented sports car.
As part of a plea deal in June 2009, Brown pleads guilty to one felony count of assault with the intent of doing great bodily injury. Under terms of the agreement, Brown is given five years of probation and ordered to serve 180 days in jail or the equivalent in labor-oriented community service.
Brown and his mother appear on CNN's "Larry King Live" on September 2, 2009. It was his first television interview since his arrest. "I've said countless times how sorry I am to Rihanna, and I just accepted full responsibility," Brown said. "But it's just one of those things I wish I could have relived and just handled totally different."
In June 2010, Brown broke down in tears during his performance of "Man in the Mirror" at the BET Awards in Los Angeles.
"Takers," an action drama co-starring Brown, premiered in August 2010.
In 2011, Brown's album "F.A.M.E." debuted at No. 1 on the Billboard 200 chart. Here, he performs that summer on NBC's "Today" show.
In February 2012, Brown's career appeared to be on an upswing following his legal woes. "F.A.M.E." won a Grammy for Best R&amp;B Album.
In March 2011, Brown reportedly stormed off the set of ABC's "Good Morning America" after he was interviewed by Robin Roberts. He later apologized.
Brown performs during the Billboard Music Awards in May 2012.
Brown and rapper Drake, seen here in 2010, reportedly got into an altercation at the New York City club W.i.P. in June 2012. Brown was left with a cut on his chin.
Brown appears in court for a probation progress report hearing in February 2013. In a court filing, prosecutors accused Brown of not completing the 180 days of community labor as stipulated from his 2009 felony assault case.
During a court appearance in July, a judge revoked Brown's probation. The revocation was triggered after Brown allegedly sped away from the scene of a minor traffic crash in May, failing to hand over his driver's license and insurance information to another driver.
Brown's attorney, Mark Geragos, speaks to the press after a judge dropped a hit-and-run charge against Brown in August. The singer reached a "civil compromise" with his accuser.
A judge also reinstated Brown's probation in August, signing off on 1,000 hours of "community labor" such as graffiti or beach cleanup. Two months later, Brown and a bodyguard were arrested and charged with felony assault after allegedly attacking a man with their fists outside the W Hotel in downtown Washington.
Brown, center, departs the H. Carl Moultrie Courthouse in Washington on Monday, October 28. The assault charge against the singer was reduced to a misdemeanor and he was released without bail.
HIDE CAPTION
The highs and lows of Chris Brown
The highs and lows of Chris Brown
The highs and lows of Chris Brown
The highs and lows of Chris Brown
The highs and lows of Chris Brown
The highs and lows of Chris Brown
The highs and lows of Chris Brown
The highs and lows of Chris Brown
The highs and lows of Chris Brown
The highs and lows of Chris Brown
The highs and lows of Chris Brown
The highs and lows of Chris Brown
The highs and lows of Chris Brown
The highs and lows of Chris Brown
The highs and lows of Chris Brown
The highs and lows of Chris Brown
The highs and lows of Chris Brown
The highs and lows of Chris Brown
The highs and lows of Chris Brown
The highs and lows of Chris Brown
The highs and lows of Chris Brown
&lt;&lt;
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
