<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 10:10:45 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_entertainment" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_entertainment"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Madonna: Highest paid musician of 2013</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2013/11/20/showbiz/celebrity-news-gossip/madonna-higest-paid-celebs-gallery/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~3/XT7ugt7IfjU/index.html</link>
<description>&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~4/XT7ugt7IfjU" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 10:02:38 EST</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.cnn.com/2013/11/20/showbiz/celebrity-news-gossip/madonna-higest-paid-celebs-gallery/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Madonna and the other highest paid celebs of 2013
November 20, 2013 -- Updated 1702 GMT (0102 HKT)
Madonna brought in an estimated $125 million in the past year, making her the highest-paid celebrity of 2013 . Just to rub a little salt in the wounds of her competitors, Forbes also crowned the Material Girl as this year's highest-paid musician in the world . It's not lonely at the top though: Check out others joining Madge as one of the top-paid stars of 2013.
Ashton Kutcher's turn as Steve Jobs didn't go so well -- the summer release has only grossed $16 million since it opened in August -- but his work on "Two and a Half Men" is lucrative. According to Forbes , the 35-year-old actor has earned roughly $24 million between June 2012 and June 2013.
No wonder Sofia Vergara is always smiling. The "Modern Family" actress has about 30 million reasons to, seeing as that's how many dollars she's estimated to have raked in over the past year. That $30 million made Vergara, 41, the highest-paid TV actress on Forbes' list for the second year in a row.
If Robert Downey Jr. keeps making Marvel movies, he might come close to amassing a fortune to rival his heroic character, Iron Man. The 48-year-old star has rebounded from his not-so-distant career lows to become the highest-paid actor in Hollywood this year , earning an estimated $75 million.
Beyoncè and Jay-Z are prime examples of a "power couple," and not just because they're the best-paid pair in Hollywood. According to Forbes, these two entertainment megastars earned an estimated $95 million in the past year combined.
E.L. James' next book could be called "Fifty Shades" of money green. The writer, whose "Twilight"-inspired fan fiction has spawned the best-selling trilogy "Fifty Shades of Grey," earned an estimated $95 million in the past year. That makes her Forbes' top-earning author of 2013 .
When it comes down to the financial king of Hollywood, legend Steven Spielberg is the man who wears the crown. The 66-year-old filmmaker is at the top of Forbes' list of the highest-paid male celebrities , with an estimated $100 million to his name in the past year.
For the under-30 set, it's 27-year-old Lady Gaga who's at the top of the list. The artist earned an estimated $80 million in the past year -- no wonder she could afford a 24-karat gold wheelchair upon her recovery from hip surgery.
Simon Cowell's 2013 payday is enough to keep him stocked in snug V-neck T-shirts and set up a trust fund for his pending arrival . The current "X Factor" judge, 54, shares the title of top-earning TV personality this year, having made an estimated $95 million this past year. You know who else brought in that sizeable amount?
"America's Got Talent" judge and radio star Howard Stern. Along with Cowell, 59-year-old Stern is No. 1 on Forbes' list of top-earning TV personalities for 2013.
Granted, Oprah Winfrey's earnings took a tumble in the past year as she continued to transition from hosting her own daytime talk show to truly being on her OWN as a CEO. But never underestimate the reach of the media mogul's influence. The 59-year-old, who earned an estimated $77 million between June 2012 and June 2013, is Forbes' most powerful celebrity of the year.
HIDE CAPTION
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
