<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 10:34:11 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Bolshoi dancer jailed for acid attack</title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/12/03/world/europe/russia-bolshoi-acid-attack/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/12/03/world/europe/russia-bolshoi-acid-attack/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>Three men are convicted of masterminding and carrying out an acid attack on the Bolshoi Ballet's artistic director, Sergei Filin.</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 07:15:02 EST</pubDate>
<ExtractedText>3 men sentenced in Bolshoi Ballet acid attack case
By Atika Shubert and Alla Eshchenko, CNN
December 3, 2013 -- Updated 1309 GMT (2109 HKT)
Pavel Dmitrichenko, a leading dancer at Russias Bolshoi Theatre, looks on as he stands inside the defendant's cage during a court hearing in Moscow, on October 22, 2013.
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
NEW: Dancer Pavel Dmitrichenko is given a six-year prison term for masterminding the attack
Accomplice Yuri Zarutsky and driver Andrei Lipatov are also convicted
The acid attack almost blinded the Bolshoi Ballet's artistic director, Sergei Filin
The case has exposed rivalries and tensions at the world-renowned ballet company
Moscow (CNN) -- Three men were convicted and sentenced Tuesday in Russia for masterminding and carrying out an acid attack on the Bolshoi Ballet's artistic director , Sergei Filin.
Star dancer Pavel Dmitrichenko was given six years in prison for masterminding the attack, while accomplice Yuri Zarutsky was sentenced to 10 years and driver Andrei Lipatov got four years, a reporter for the official Russian Legal Information Agency (RAPSI) who was in court told CNN.
Prosecutors at the Moscow court had asked for Dmitrichenko to be given nine years in prison, RAPSI reported earlier.
Filin was walking to his Moscow apartment in January when a masked assailant tossed sulfuric acid onto his face, leaving him severely burned and nearly blinded.
Dancer found guilty in acid attack
Bolshoi director puts conflicts in past
Former dancer: Bolshoi acts like brothel
He has spent much of the past year in Germany, where doctors have been working to save his sight.
Curtain falls on Russian ballet director after tumultuous year
The case, which has been closely watched in Russia and elsewhere, has exposed the tensions and intrigues simmering below the surface at the world-renowned ballet company.
Dmitrichenko argued during his trial that he had wanted Filin to be punished in some way for failing to give him the roles he wanted; for example, by being beaten up. But, the dancer said, he did not expect Filin to be subjected to an acid attack.
In his evidence, Zarutsky told the court that the acid attack was his own idea and that he had not told Dmitrichenko about it.
Many fellow Bolshoi dancers signed a letter asking the judge for leniency for Dmitrichenko.
In his summary, the judge said that in his view, the attack was organized by Dmitrichenko.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
