<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 10:34:11 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Rowdy football fans spark 'earthquake'</title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/12/03/us/seattle-seahawks-earthquake/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/12/03/us/seattle-seahawks-earthquake/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>There's no need to tell football fans in Seattle to take it up a notch. They're doing just fine, thank you.</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 09:47:32 EST</pubDate>
<ExtractedText>Rowdy Seattle Seahawks fans register as earthquake during Monday Night Football
By Justin Lear and Ed Payne, CNN
December 3, 2013 -- Updated 1447 GMT (2247 HKT)
Matt Roe, an acoustical consultant with SSA Acoustics, measures noise levels in CenturyLink Field.
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
Fans rock the stadium and show up on an earthquake recording system
The Seattle-New Orleans game produced five seismic events
A college in Louisiana also appeared as an earthquake in 1988
The Seahawks beat the Saints, 34-7
(CNN) -- There's no need to tell football fans in Seattle to take it up a notch. They're doing just fine, thank you.
After setting a Guinness World Record for noise at an outdoor stadium in September , CenturyLink Field went seismic during Monday Night Football, registering as an earthquake at a recording station about a block from the stadium.
How big, you ask?
In the magnitude 1-to-2 range, according to John Vidale, a professor at the University of Washington and the director of the Pacific Northwest Seismic Network.
Vidale said his staff recorded five separate seismic events during Seattle's 34-7 pasting of New Orleans -- a match-up of two of the NFL's top teams.
The most intense episode came late in the first quarter, when Seahawks defensive lineman Michael Bennett returned a Saints fumble 22 yards for a touchdown.
Seattle fans did this once before. In 2011, a Marshawn Lynch touchdown shook the earthquake recording station too.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
