<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 10:34:11 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Truce in Bangkok</title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/05/01/world/defining-moments/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/05/01/world/defining-moments/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description/>
<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 06:39:31 EST</pubDate>
<ExtractedText>By Monica Sarkar and Ivana Kottasová , CNN
November 29, 2013 -- Updated 1253 GMT (2053 HKT)
DECEMBER 3 - BANGKOK, THAILAND: A Buddhist monk raises his hands to policemen in Bangkok. Tensions in the capital eased after police took down barricades and allowed anti-government demonstrators to enter the government buildings. Policemen shook hands with demonstrators, ushering them past. Protesters responded with cheers and applause, claiming victory.
DECEMBER 2 - JERUSALEM: An Ultra-Orthodox Jewish man and his child light candles on the fifth night of the Jewish holiday of Hanukkah , the Festival of light. The holiday commemorates the victory of the Maccabees over the Syrians and the re-dedication of the Second Temple of Jerusalem around 165 BC after the Greek King of Syria outlawed Jewish rituals.
NOVEMBER 29 - SOFIA, BULGARIA: Syrian refugee children play at the recently opened Vrazhdebna shelter in Sofia. A new report released today says 1.1 million Syrian refugees are children . Most of them live in neighboring countries, with no access to education. Here's how you can help the children on Syria.
NOVEMBER 28 - SKOPJE, MACEDONIA: People plant trees on a hill just east of Skopje. Around 5 million seedlings were planted during the country's annual "Tree Day" campaign which aims to raise awareness of deforestation. Nearly 50 million trees have been planted as part of the "Plant your future" campaign since it began in 2008.
NOVEMBER 27 - NEW DELHI, INDIA: An Indian man attends a protest demanding a universal pension of U.S.$32 per month for those above 60 years of age. The central government has proposed a pension of U.S.$3 per month. India is currently home to more than 100 million people aged 60 and over.
NOVEMBER 26 - ST. PETER'S BASILICA: Pope Francis meets Ukrainian Major Archbishop Sviatoslav Shevchuk. Vatican marks the conclusion of the Catholic church's "Year of Faith" this week. The bones of a man long believed to be St. Peter , one of the founding fathers of the Christian church, are on display for the first time.
NOVEMBER 25 - KARO, INDONESIA: A series of eruptions from Mount Sinabung volcano prompted authorities to raise the alert status to the highest level on Sunday. About 15,000 people have been evacuated from 17 villages in the danger zone , a 5-kilometer (3-mile) area around the crater, said the National Disaster Mitigation Agency.
NOVEMBER 22 - PHNOM PENH, CAMBODIA : Activist Yorm Bopha arrives at court for her appeal trial. Declared a prisoner of conscience by Amnesty International, Bopha has been granted bail after 444 days in jail. She opposes land grabs by the Cambodian government , which has forcibly evicted over 700,000 people over the past decade.
NOVEMBER 21 - ALLAHABAD, INDIA: An Indian girl sits outside her home in a slum. Newly released census data shows families living in slums have a far better child sex ratio than the urban Indian average. The ratio of children aged 0 to 6 years old in an average slum household is 923 girls to every 1,000 boys, compared to 905 for urban households.
NOVEMBER 20 - ISLAMABAD, PAKISTAN: Official statistics released by the Federal Education Ministry of Pakistan give a desperate picture of education for all, especially girls, in the country. The overall literacy rate is 46 percent, while only 26 per cent of girls are literate. Pictured here, Afghan refugee girls attend a makeshift school set up in a mosque on the outskirts of the city.
NOVEMBER 19 - TACLOBAN, PHILIPPINES: A young boy takes a shower at a school which has been turned into a temporary shelter in Tacloban. Nearly 4,000 people died and hundreds of thousands were displaced by Typhoon Haiyan , which tore across several islands in the eastern Philippines on November 8.
NOVEMBER 18 - JAFFNA, SRI LANKA: A Tamil fisherman paddles his boat along the shoreline. Meanwhile in the capital Colombo, Commonwealth leaders signed agreements on issues such as poverty and development as they staged a show of unity after a summit dominated by a bitter dispute over war crimes claims .
NOVEMBER 15 - BIJAR, IRAN: Shiite Muslims cover themselves in mud during Ashura rituals. The holiday marks the death of Imam Hussein, the grandson of Islam's Prophet Muhammad and one of Shiite Islam's most beloved saints. Ashura celebrations are vital to the Shiite minority, who, unlike the Sunni, believe he is the rightful successor of Mohammed.
NOVEMBER 14 - IN SPACE: NASA has unveiled this image of the planet Saturn back lit by the sun. The photo was taken four months ago from the Cassini spacecraft. The ringed planet spans 404,880 miles (651,591 kilometers) across and Mars, Venus and Earth, are also visible in the picture.
NOVEMBER 13 - CUIABA, BRAZIL: Gaviao Indians participate in a tug of war competition during the 12th International Games of Indigenous People. Forty-eight indigenous tribes will present their cultural rituals during the games, which run until November 16.
NOVEMBER 12 - BEIJING, CHINA: A Chinese paramilitary officer patrols Tiananmen Square in front of the Great Hall of the People after the Communist Party concluded its third plenum. China watchers will be looking closely to see if this gathering becomes a launchpad for major new reforms , as the meetings have in the past.
NOVEMBER 11 - TACLOBAN, PHILIPPINES: Emily Ortega rests after giving birth to Bea Joy at an improvised clinic at Tacloban airport . Ortega had to swim to survive before finding safety at the airport when the storm flooded the city. The baby was named after her grandmother Beatrice, who is missing following the onslaught of typhoon Haiyan .
NOVEMBER 8 - CEBU CITY, PHILIPPINES: Filipinos brave powerful winds as Typhoon Haiyan pounds the country. The storm is perhaps one of the strongest ever recorded on the planet. It smashed into island after island across the central Philippines on Friday, threatening millions of people.
NOVEMBER 7 - KAZAKHSTAN: Cameramen film as the Olympic torch leaves Earth as part of its 123-day journey across Russia via the International Space Station, ending at the Black Sea resort of Sochi -- host venue for the 2014 Winter Games. The rocket was launched at 8:14 a.m. local time at the Baikonur Cosmodrome, which is a Russian-leased facility.
NOVEMBER 6 - NEW YORK CITY, U.S.: Newly-elected New York City Mayor Bill de Blasio waves to the crowd at his election night party on November 5. De Blasio will be the first Democratic mayor in New York City in two decades, after easily defeating Republican Joe Lhota by running a campaign that rejected the politics of his predecessor, Michael Bloomberg.
NOVEMBER 05 - MELBOURNE, AUSTRALIA: First run in 1861, Australia's $6 million Melbourne Cup is known as "the race that stops a nation." The 2013 contest was won by the favorite, Fiorente , ridden by Damien Oliver. More than 350,000 people attend the event, with hundreds of racegoers taking part in the "Fashions on the Field" competition .
NOVEMBER 4 - RAJASTHAN, INDIA: A man watches Diwali fireworks light up the night sky above Ajmer town. Millions of Indians set off fireworks for the Hindu Festival of Lights , which celebrates the triumph of good over evil.
NOVEMBER 1 - MADRID, SPAIN: A man walks through central Madrid while checking his phone. After Germany and France, Spain became the latest country to learn about U.S. intelligence spying on its citizens . Spanish media reported earlier this week that the NSA collected data from 60 million phone calls in the country .
OCTOBER 31 - MANILA, PHILIPPINES: Youngsters play basketball at a cemetery, marking one of the most important holidays for the largest Catholic nation in Asia, All Saints' Day . Filipinos traditionally visit cemeteries to hold vigils and large family reunions, but the atmosphere is far from sad, as the usually silent graveyards turn into parties with food and music.
OCTOBER 30 - GAZA: Palestinian prisoners' relatives wait behind a fence for their release at the Erez Crossing in northern Gaza on October 29. Israel freed 26 veteran prisoners early on October 30 as part of a deal put together by the U.S. to jump-start stalled Israeli-Palestinian peace talks.
OCTOBER 29 - CAIRO, EGYPT: Student supporters of ousted president Mohamed Morsy and the Muslim Brotherhood light up a flare as they demonstrate outside al-Azhar university in Cairo on October 28. Since Morsy's ouster and detention in July, his supporters have continued to take to the streets.
OCTOBER 28 - BOULOGNE, FRANCE: Large waves break against the harbor wall at the entrance of the port of Boulogne, northern France, on October 28, 2013. A fierce storm battered Europe and the south of England, leaving at least two people dead. Weather forecasters had said before the storm arrived that it could be the region's worst in a decade.
OCTOBER 25 - RAWALPINDI, PAKISTAN: 13-year-old Awais Shaukat lies in bed, sick with dengue fever . Dengue, a flu-like illness, is spread by the Aedes mosquito and unlike malaria, there are no drugs to prevent it. It spikes during the annual monsoons, when the insects breed in puddles of stagnant water. So far, attempts to develop a vaccine have been unsuccessful .
OCTOBER 24 - KABUL, AFGHANISTAN: Recruits perform drills at the Afghanistan National Army Officers' Academy. Afghans now lead security operations at home , with the remaining international forces responding only when asked. NATO troops are scheduled to leave in 2014.
OCTOBER 23 - YOGYAKARTA, INDONESIA: Rizki a five-year-old volunteer at Kraton, the Yogyakarta Sultanate's royal palace, attends the wedding of one of the five daughters of Sultan Hamengkubuwono X. The wedding celebrations will take three days, include a parade of 12 royal horse-drawn carriages, and culminate with the wedding vows.
HIDE CAPTION
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
