<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 10:34:11 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Is this the airport of the future?</title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/12/03/business/airport-of-the-future/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/12/03/business/airport-of-the-future/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>Sleep pods, yoga rooms and baggage scanners: What will the airport of the future look like?</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 07:43:11 EST</pubDate>
<ExtractedText>Step inside the airport of the future
December 3, 2013 -- Updated 1304 GMT (2104 HKT)
What will the airport of the tomorrow look like? We've compiled some of the most exciting projects in an interactive feature.
Could port herald new age for Cuba?
November 20, 2013 -- Updated 1205 GMT (2005 HKT)
In the sleepy seaside town of Mariel, northwest Cuba, a hulking monument to the communist islands' evolving economy is taking shape.
Sailor who stared down Somali pirates
November 26, 2013 -- Updated 1353 GMT (2153 HKT)
Meet Russian Tugboat captain, Viktor Nikolsky, who has sailed the world's seas and survived being hijacked by Somali pirates.
November 8, 2013 -- Updated 1039 GMT (1839 HKT)
Meet Sergey Matveev and family, St Petersburg's "First Family" of drawbridge operators.
October 31, 2013 -- Updated 1159 GMT (1959 HKT)
Where are the world's most dangerous waters? Hint; they're not off the coast of Somalia.
Most spectacular train stations
October 17, 2013 -- Updated 1122 GMT (1922 HKT)
Train and metro stations have become unlikely havens for some of the most exquisite architecture and design. We profile some of the best.
Ducks overboard!
October 9, 2013 -- Updated 1239 GMT (2039 HKT)
What have 29,000 plastic toys that fell overboard a cargo ship in 1992 been doing for the last 21 years?
October 4, 2013 -- Updated 1340 GMT (2140 HKT)
How are ports adapting to cope with the new generation of giant cargo ships?
Where is the world's busiest airport?
September 27, 2013 -- Updated 1152 GMT (1952 HKT)
London, Beijing or somewhere in the United States: Where is the world's busiest airport? Find out in our detailed infographic.
September 13, 2013 -- Updated 0927 GMT (1727 HKT)
Urban gondolas are offering cheap and effective methods of mass-transportation in some of South America's biggest cities.
Linking Europe and Asia by rail
June 27, 2013 -- Updated 0923 GMT (1723 HKT)
The Silk Road was once a series of dusty trails forged by traders traveling between Asia and Europe. Today it takes the form of a bustling railway.
Introducing the world's biggest ship
June 26, 2013 -- Updated 1249 GMT (2049 HKT)
An all new class of container ship, the Triple E is a quarter-of-a-mile long and built from enough steel to construct 8 Eiffel Towers.
8 spectacular infrastructure projects
June 18, 2013 -- Updated 1136 GMT (1936 HKT)
Take a peek at some of the most exciting travel infrastructure projects currently in the works around the world.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
