<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 10:34:11 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>China looms over war drills</title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/11/28/world/asia/japan-us-annualex-war-games/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/11/28/world/asia/japan-us-annualex-war-games/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>This year's war games have an added dimension given the high-pressure atmosphere in the East China Sea</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:30:00 EST</pubDate>
<ExtractedText>USS George Washington in huge naval exercise -- AnnualEx 2013 -- off Okinawa
CNN reporter aboard carrier as dozens of warships, subs and aircraft take part
This year's games held against backdrop of tension after China imposes new air zone
China announced a new Air Defense Identification Zone, angering U.S. and Japan
USS George Washington, East China Sea (CNN) -- The deafening roar of state-of-the-art warplanes being catapulted into the air from its huge flight deck signaled that the USS George Washington was back in combat mode after its recent detour to the Philippines to take part in the aid effort in the wake of Super Typhoon Haiyan.
Barely a week on and the 90,000-ton Nimitz-class aircraft carrier is now patrolling waters off the island of Okinawa as part a huge naval exercise -- AnnualEx 2013 -- involving dozens of warships, submarines and aircraft from the U.S. Navy's 7th fleet and the Japan Maritime Self-Defense Force (JMSDF).
The aim? To provide a stern test of their ability to effectively and mutually respond to the defense of Japan or to a regional crisis or contingency situation in the Indo-Asia-Pacific region, according to the U.S. Navy.
But this year's war games have taken on an added dimension given the high-pressure atmosphere in the region at present -- they take place in the shadow of a controversial new Air Defense Identification Zone announced by the Chinese last weekend.
 Map showing the controversial air defense identification zone in the East China Sea.
Map showing the controversial air defense identification zone in the East China Sea.
Japan balks at China's territory claim
Amb. Kennedy: China undermining security
Beijing and Tokyo dispute over islands
Shipbuilders in Newport News, Virginia, prepare to flood a dry dock to float what will be the USS Gerald R. Ford, the first ship in the U.S. Navy's newest class of aircraft carriers. Click through the gallery to see photos of other carrier classes throughout American history.
U.S. Navy Boatswain's Mate Ben Hansen and his wife Jessica, of Edmore Mich., are photographed in front of the Navy's newest nuclear-powered aircraft carrier, the USS Gerald R. Ford, during the christening of the ship at Newport News Shipbuilding in Newport News, Virginia, on Saturday, November 9. The late president's daughter, Susan Ford Bales, christened the ship.
Lightning strikes over the flight deck of the USS John C. Stennis, a Nimitz-class aircraft carrier, as the ship moves through the Persian Gulf in 2007. All of the Navy's 10 active aircraft carriers are from the Nimitz class, which started in 1975 with the commission of the USS Nimitz.
Aircrew members are lifted from the flight deck of the USS John F. Kennedy during an exercise in 2002. The ship, which was decommissioned in 2007, was the only member of its class.
An F/A-18 Hornet launches from the USS Enterprise in 2007. The Enterprise, the world's first nuclear-powered aircraft carrier, was decommissioned in 2012. Like the John F. Kennedy, it was the only ship built in its class.
The Kitty Hawk class was named for the USS Kitty Hawk, seen here departing Yokosuka, Japan, in 2008. At that time, the Kitty Hawk was the oldest carrier in the U.S. Navy and the only conventional-powered aircraft carrier still in commission. It was decommissioned in 2009.
The USS Independence, a member of the Forrestal class that preceded the Kitty Hawk class, heads up the East River in New York in 1959.
Helicopters sit on the flight deck of the USS Saipan during the mid-1950s. The ship was one of two members of the Saipan class.
The USS Midway, namesake of the Midway class of aircraft carriers, floats off the coast of North Vietnam in 1972. It was named after the Battle of Midway, when U.S. forces held back a Japanese attempt to take the Hawaiian island in 1942.
The USS Princeton, part of the Independence class, moves off the coast of Seattle in 1944.
The Essex-class USS Franklin burns after being hit by a Japanese dive bomber in 1945. The ship was named after Benjamin Franklin and nicknamed "Big Ben."
The USS Wasp burns in the Coral Sea after being struck by three torpedoes from a Japanese submarine in 1942. The ship, the only one of its class, would eventually sink because of the damage.
B-25 bombers sit on the deck of the USS Hornet in the Pacific Ocean in 1942. The Hornet, one of three ships in the Yorktown class, was the ship that launched bombers flown by Air Force Lt. Col. James Doolittle and his pilots during an air raid in Tokyo four months after the attack on Pearl Harbor.
A man looks over the flight deck of the USS Ranger in Pearl Harbor in 1964. The Ranger was the first ship to be designed and built as an aircraft carrier from the beginning. It was the only ship in its class.
Crew members of the USS Saratoga, named after the New York town where British forces surrendered to American revolutionary soldiers in the 18th century, cover the deck as the ship moves towards the Golden Gate Bridge in San Francisco in 1945. The ship was one of two members in the Lexington class of aircraft carriers.
The USS Langley, the U.S. Navy's first aircraft carrier and sole member of its class, is seen off the coast of Baltimore in 1924.
U.S. aircraft carrier classes
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
