<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Sports: Sports News, Scores, Analysis, Schedules &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/2010/07/08/AB582vC_page.html?wprss=rss_sports</link>
<description>The Washington Post Sports section provides sports news, video, scores, analysis and updates about high school, college, and pro sports teams, including the Capitals, Nationals, Redskins, United and Wizards. Post Sports also offers blogs and discussions about the latest sports news.</description>
<language>en</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2012 Washington Post Company</copyright>
<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 14:54:05 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 14:54:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>Sports: Sports News, Scores, Analysis, Schedules &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<url>http://media3.washingtonpost.com/wp-srv/hp/image/wp_web.gif</url>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/2010/07/08/AB582vC_page.html?wprss=rss_sports</link>
</image>
<item>
<title>Wise: Mike Shanahan tried to stick with Robert Griffin III, and might have lost him instead</title>
<link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636679/s/34597de6/sc/13/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Csports0Credskins0Cmike0Eshanahan0Etried0Eto0Estick0Ewith0Erobert0Egriffin0Eiii0Eand0Emight0Ehave0Elost0Ehim0Einstead0C20A130C120C0A20C656d75bc0E5ba60E11e30Ea66d0E156b463c78aa0Istory0Bhtml0Dwprss0Frss0Isports/story01.htm</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;On the heels of &lt;a data-xslt="_http" href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/football-insider/wp/2013/12/02/redskins-officially-eliminated-from-playoff-contention/"&gt;playoff hope being snuffed out&lt;/a&gt; Sunday &lt;a data-xslt="_http" href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/redskins-vs-giants-washington-lets-an-early-lead-and-late-chances-slip-away-in-24-17-loss/2013/12/01/d10217ae-5ab8-11e3-bf7e-f567ee61ae21_story.html"&gt;against the New York Giants&lt;/a&gt; a full month before the season officially concludes, let’s first operate on one clear premise: This season was on very unstable ground before it began. All attempts to obfuscate or minimize the tensions between the divergent camps of the coach and the quarterback, in hindsight, were either damage control or outright denial.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/redskins/mike-shanahan-tried-to-stick-with-robert-griffin-iii-and-might-have-lost-him-instead/2013/12/02/656d75bc-5ba6-11e3-a66d-156b463c78aa_story.html?wprss=rss_sports"&gt;Read full article &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636679/s/34597de6/sc/13/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;div class='mf-viral'&gt;&lt;table border='0'&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td valign='middle'&gt;&lt;a href="http://share.feedsportal.com/share/twitter/?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.washingtonpost.com%2Fsports%2Fredskins%2Fmike-shanahan-tried-to-stick-with-robert-griffin-iii-and-might-have-lost-him-instead%2F2013%2F12%2F02%2F656d75bc-5ba6-11e3-a66d-156b463c78aa_story.html%3Fwprss%3Drss_sports&amp;t=Wise%3A+Mike+Shanahan+tried+to+stick+with+Robert+Griffin+III%2C+and+might+have+lost+him+instead" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://res3.feedsportal.com/social/twitter.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://share.feedsportal.com/share/facebook/?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.washingtonpost.com%2Fsports%2Fredskins%2Fmike-shanahan-tried-to-stick-with-robert-griffin-iii-and-might-have-lost-him-instead%2F2013%2F12%2F02%2F656d75bc-5ba6-11e3-a66d-156b463c78aa_story.html%3Fwprss%3Drss_sports&amp;t=Wise%3A+Mike+Shanahan+tried+to+stick+with+Robert+Griffin+III%2C+and+might+have+lost+him+instead" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://res3.feedsportal.com/social/facebook.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://share.feedsportal.com/share/linkedin/?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.washingtonpost.com%2Fsports%2Fredskins%2Fmike-shanahan-tried-to-stick-with-robert-griffin-iii-and-might-have-lost-him-instead%2F2013%2F12%2F02%2F656d75bc-5ba6-11e3-a66d-156b463c78aa_story.html%3Fwprss%3Drss_sports&amp;t=Wise%3A+Mike+Shanahan+tried+to+stick+with+Robert+Griffin+III%2C+and+might+have+lost+him+instead" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://res3.feedsportal.com/social/linkedin.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://share.feedsportal.com/share/gplus/?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.washingtonpost.com%2Fsports%2Fredskins%2Fmike-shanahan-tried-to-stick-with-robert-griffin-iii-and-might-have-lost-him-instead%2F2013%2F12%2F02%2F656d75bc-5ba6-11e3-a66d-156b463c78aa_story.html%3Fwprss%3Drss_sports&amp;t=Wise%3A+Mike+Shanahan+tried+to+stick+with+Robert+Griffin+III%2C+and+might+have+lost+him+instead" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://res3.feedsportal.com/social/googleplus.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://share.feedsportal.com/share/email/?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.washingtonpost.com%2Fsports%2Fredskins%2Fmike-shanahan-tried-to-stick-with-robert-griffin-iii-and-might-have-lost-him-instead%2F2013%2F12%2F02%2F656d75bc-5ba6-11e3-a66d-156b463c78aa_story.html%3Fwprss%3Drss_sports&amp;t=Wise%3A+Mike+Shanahan+tried+to+stick+with+Robert+Griffin+III%2C+and+might+have+lost+him+instead" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://res3.feedsportal.com/social/email.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<category domain="">Mike Shanahan</category>
<category domain="">National Football League</category>
<category domain="">offensive coordinator</category>
<category domain="">hp</category>
<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 00:48:21 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/redskins/mike-shanahan-tried-to-stick-with-robert-griffin-iii-and-might-have-lost-him-instead/2013/12/02/656d75bc-5ba6-11e3-a66d-156b463c78aa_story.html?wprss=rss_sports</guid>
<dc:creator>Mike Wise</dc:creator>
<ExtractedText>Columnist
Mike Shanahan tried to stick with Robert Griffin III, and might have lost him instead
Video: The Washington Post's Mike Jones analyzes what's in store for the Redskins when they take on the Kansas City Chiefs on Sunday.
By Mike Wise , E-mail the writer
On the heels of playoff hope being snuffed out Sunday against the New York Giants a full month before the season officially concludes, let’s first operate on one clear premise: This season was on very unstable ground before it began. All attempts to obfuscate or minimize the tensions between the divergent camps of the coach and the quarterback, in hindsight, were either damage control or outright denial.
It’s why Mike Shanahan raised eyebrows when, asked repeatedly why Alfred Morris didn’t carry the ball more in the loss to New York, said there were option-pitch plays for Morris but that Robert Griffin III decided to keep the ball and run himself in those instances.
twitter
Gallery
It wasn’t fun even while it lasted
Tracee Hamilton
Sunday night’s game was the latest act in a season-long theater of the absurd for the Washington Redskins.
Mike Jones
The Redskins no longer have postseason hopes, but the coach says he'll still play the best players.
Shanahan-Griffin: An unmendable tear?
Mike Wise
In trying to show loyalty to his franchise QB 11 months ago, coach made decision that still reverberates.
Redskins vs. Giants: Early lead, late chances slip away
Mark Maske
Washington lost 24-17, falling to 3-9 despite an early 14-0 lead and a good game from Robert Griffin III.
Griffin not a problem this time
Kent Babb
With a tailored game plan, Robert Griffin III passes efficiently and runs well, yet his teammates let him down.
Mike Jones
Washington’s strong start against the Giants is undone by a mountain of penalties, drops and turnovers.
Given all the he-said, he-said history between the coach and the quarterback this season, Shanahan couldn’t just be candid in the moment. Every word had to be parsed, examined. There had to be something else.
And, of course, there was. There always has been.
The truth: Soon after Griffin’s devastating knee injury last January, Shanahan reached out to the Griffin family. Putting himself in the shoes of Griffin’s parents — knowing he would want the same clarity if it were his child writhing in pain on the ground of FedEx Field in the waning moments of that playoff loss to Seattle and had undergone major knee surgery — the coach merely wanted to explain what led up to the most crucial, in-game, on-the-fly decision of his tenure in Washington .
Shanahan eventually was able to communicate those thoughts — but not before he was originally rebuffed, according to people on both sides with knowledge of last January’s events who spoke on condition of anonymity in interviews over the past three weeks.
Robert Griffin Jr. appreciated the coach’s gesture. But he also felt Shanahan needed to worry strictly about coaching his football team rather than building a stronger bond with his son, that what’s done is done and that both parties needed to move forward and concentrate on ensuring Griffin’s health wasn’t put in jeopardy again by anyone or anything — ego, play-calling or the quarterback’s own stubborn pride.
A point of clarification here: The source of the Griffins’ discontent over the whole episode wasn’t that a gimpy Robert was allowed to continue playing, especially because he did everything but beg to be on the field; no, it was the play-calling of Kyle Shanahan, the team’s offensive coordinator and Mike’s son, after Griffin was first hurt that they felt put him at further risk.
That led to an offseason of ominous tweets, texts to ESPN anchors and quotes the next few months from Griffin and his father. Remember “a running quarterback is a losing quarterback”?
Though Shanahan did eventually convey some regret in his decision privately to Griffin, he refused to take blame publicly for what he claimed was a mutual decision made by all parties involved (himself, orthopedic surgeon James Andrews and Griffin).
That fateful day last January was the backdrop to everything this season. It became a larger story than Griffin’s rehabilitation, forking into how Griffin should be used at quarterback going forward. It carried over into training camp, with dueling notions of whether Griffin should play in the preseason and why he essentially was put in bubble-wrap before the season began.
Continued
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
