<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Business</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/BUSINESS/index.html?eref=rss_business</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 09:33:11 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Business</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/BUSINESS/index.html?eref=rss_business</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_business" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_business"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Embrace "mobile first" strategy or fail</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://edition.cnn.com/2013/12/02/business/want-to-go-global-put-mobile-first/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_business/~3/5Bp7AEtVyrE/index.html</link>
<description>Tablet sales are predicted to overtake PCs and laptops by 2015. So why are 60% of the Fortune 1000 companies still ignoring the platform and the business growth it can bring?&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_business/~4/5Bp7AEtVyrE" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 22:17:41 EST</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/12/02/business/want-to-go-global-put-mobile-first/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Want to go global? Put mobile first
By Nic Newman , MD and Head of Strategy at Tigerspike, Special to CNN
December 2, 2013 -- Updated 1445 GMT (2245 HKT)
Fall is coming, which means smartphone manufacturers will be launching new models with flashy new bells and whistles. But some forward-looking features are already part of existing phones. Here are five helpful features that other phone makers (Apple, are you listening?) would be wise to adopt.
You'd have to be crazy to take most phones into a swimming pool. Then there's the Galaxy S4 Active, which Samsung says can be submerged in three feet of water for up to 30 minutes. Our Galaxy phone worked just fine after its camera snapped this underwater pic of Etan Horowitz, CNN's mobile editor.
Snapping self-portraits with a phone can be awkward. But a countdown timer on the HTC One (not the phone pictured here) makes it easier.
Every iPhone owner has felt nagged by the number of apps on the device that must be manually updated, seemingly every few weeks. But users of Android phones don't have that problem.
All smartphones allow notifications that pop up on your screen when you get a text, say, or a Facebook message. But what if the icons, or tiles, on your screen would display real-time updates, such as weather reports? "Live tiles" on Windows phones already do.
OK, you probably shouldn't be like this guy and play with your phone when driving. But the upcoming Moto X phone at least makes it a little safer. The Moto X lets you speak voice commands to your phone without touching it and will read your text messages aloud.
HIDE CAPTION
A countdown timer for selfies
Automatic app updates
Screen tiles showing live info
Hands-free controls for drivers
Tablet sales are predicted to surpass PCs, laptops by 2015, says Gartner
Yet 60% of businesses will not have a mobile strategy in place by 2014
Firms must have 'mobile first' strategy if they wish to go global, writes Nic Newman
Editor's note: Nic Newman is EMEA managing director and head of strategy at Tigerspike , a personal media company. Going Global showcases entrepreneurs taking their businesses around the world, tackling issues like business strategy, marketing and international logistics.
(CNN) -- The world is undergoing a mobility transformation. Since Apple launched the first iPhone in 2007, more than 100 billion apps have been downloaded from app stores by consumers worldwide.
Gartner, the market research firm, has predicted that by 2015, tablet sales will be higher than those of PCs and laptops combined. There are now more connected mobile devices on earth than there are people.
Samsung takes aim at Apple
6-second videos: The future of ads?
Inside the mobile-embedded home
Sketching out the future of mobiles
This transformation is happening much faster than the dot-com revolution of the late 1990s, and businesses are catching on. Companies are already developing 20 to 30 apps on average in the three categories of consumer, business-to-business and (B2B) and enterprise.
These are already changing the way we live and work, wherever we are. Additionally, they are changing the way businesses interact with other businesses, investors, media, customers and even their own workforce worldwide.
Despite this, Gartner estimates that 60% of the Fortune 1000 companies will not have a mobile strategy in place by 2014. In my view, having a mobile strategy is not enough for businesses to succeed globally in the years to come.
What businesses need is a "mobile first" strategy, placing mobile opportunities at the forefront of their international growth.
Read: Facebook focus on mobile first
Don't forget consumer apps
Personal media technology is already streamlining the way we deal with our daily tasks -- both in business and at home. American Express offers mobile applications that allow customers to manage their accounts on the move, improving the service as well as reducing call centre waiting times.
Through similar technology, reading the Economist has never been more enjoyable (or widespread -- as the mobile and tablet apps have been downloaded six million times). The average UK family now has ten internet connected devices.
The fact is that if consumers can't access your brand on multiple platforms, they will switch to one where they can.
Creating effective mobile software is not easy. It requires solid software development and user interface design, not to mention thorough testing.
This is perhaps why, while some 60% of organizations have consumer apps, their quality does not score high among consumers. It is not enough for the apps to be useful, people have to enjoy using them.
User experience -- how an application feels -- is paramount. For ten years, Tigerspike has been working with customers who understand that user experience is about combining design and software skills with a deep knowledge of how back end systems operate.
In the global market, good user interface must include the insightful localization, both in terms of language and content.
These are the hallmarks of the most successful global consumer apps and when companies get them right, they build better relationships and channels of information for their customers in all countries.
Read: Businesses must embrace programmable world. Or die.
Enterprise apps for a global workforce
The mobile landscape is vastly different from just a few years ago. Tablet sales are predicted to surpass PCs and laptops by 2015 according to research firm Gartner
Inez Torre/CNN
In the global work market, bring your own device policies are on the rise -- allowing employees to bring personally owned mobile devices to their workplace. Companies are therefore increasingly required to create apps for their staff -- and these need to be just as good as the consumer ones.
Gartner expects 80% of businesses to support a workforce using tablets by 2014.
Company leaders want mobile technology to increase productivity. In order to achieve this, it must be realized that the best apps are not always the ones that seek to bring the entire business to the smartphone or tablet, but the ones that are created to do a few things very well.
The Innovation Lab at Tigerspike has recently received a patent for its quantum encryption mobile technology Karacell.
It is our firm belief that this technology will transform how organizations and individuals can keep our mobile data safe on personal technology devices, with countless benefits to companies and organizations in global business.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
