<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 10:10:45 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_entertainment" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_entertainment"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>When a production loses a star </title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2013/12/02/showbiz/paul-walker-stars-died-during-production-gallery/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~3/WVOw9fOPkvQ/index.html</link>
<description>&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~4/WVOw9fOPkvQ" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 18:33:31 EST</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.cnn.com/2013/12/02/showbiz/paul-walker-stars-died-during-production-gallery/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Paul Walker and other stars who died during production
By Lisa Respers France, CNN
December 2, 2013 -- Updated 1836 GMT (0236 HKT)
The death of Paul Walker and his friend, identified by CNN affiliate KCAL as Roger Rodus, leaves some questions regarding the production of the latest "Fast &amp; Furious" movie, which was filming in Atlanta. Here's a look at other celebrities who have died during the production of movies and TV shows.
Heath Ledger was filming "The Imaginarium of Doctor Parnassus" in 2008 when he died of accidental drug intoxication. The film was completed using other actors as fantasy versions of Ledger's character.
Lee Thompson Young was appearing on TNT's "Rizzoli &amp; Isles" when he committed suicide in April.
Chris Farley, at center with filmmakers Tyron Montgomery, left, and Thomas Stellmach after they won the Oscar for best animated short film for "Quest" in 1997. Farley reportedly was working on the animated film "Shrek" when he died of an overdose in 1997. His "SNL" colleague Mike Myers would go on to snag the role.
Phil Hartman rose to fame for his impersonations including President Bill Clinton on "Saturday Night Live," but he was starring on the sitcom "NewsRadio" when he was shot to death by his wife in 1998. Actor Jon Lovitz replaced him.
Jon-Erik Hexum was a 26-year-old rising star in 1984 when he shot himself with a prop gun on the set of his new TV series, "Cover Up." The blank drove a piece of his skull into his brain, and he was taken off of life support a week later. His character was killed off
Brandon Lee was filming the movie "The Crow" in 1993 when he was accidentally shot and killed during a scene. Lee was the son of ...
Actor and martial arts expert Bruce Lee, who was working on dubbing the film "Enter the Dragon" when he died in 1973 of a brain edema, caused by a prescription painkiller.
Vic Morrow, here in "The Streets of San Francisco" in 1973, died along with two child actors in 1982 when a stunt helicopter crashed on top of them during the filming of "Twilight Zone: The Movie." The accident resulted in an involuntary manslaughter case against director John Landis and four others. The group was ultimately acquitted.
Cory Monteith's death in July at the age of 31 from mixed drug toxicity combined with alcohol meant his hit show, "Glee," had to figure out how best to deal with his character. Monteith's character, Finn Hudson, center, also died on the series, though the cause of death was not revealed.
John Ritter died of an aortic dissection at the height of his show "8 Simple Rules" in 2003. David Spade and James Garner were later cast.
River Phoenix was almost finished filming "Dark Blood" when he died of drug-induced heart failure in 1993. It would take 19 years for the film to be completed.
"The Royal Family" was in rehearsals when Redd Foxx died of a heart attack in 1991. The TV comedy had been intended as a comeback vehicle for Foxx and did not survive long after his death.
Freddie Prinze, left, was starring on "Chico and the Man" when he fatally shot himself in 1977. Child actor Gabriel Melgar was brought in to play a new character, Raul, after Prinze's death.
When John Spencer died of a heart attack in 2005, his character on "The West Wing," Leo McGarry, suffered the same fate.
Natalie Wood mysteriously drowned in 1981 near Santa Catalina Island, California, during production of the science fiction film "Brainstorm." Her co-star, Christopher Walken, was sailing with the actress and her husband, Robert Wagner, at the time.
HIDE CAPTION
Stars who died during production
Stars who died during production
Stars who died during production
Stars who died during production
Stars who died during production
Stars who died during production
Stars who died during production
Stars who died during production
Stars who died during production
Stars who died during production
Stars who died during production
Stars who died during production
Stars who died during production
Stars who died during production
Stars who died during production
Stars who died during production
&lt;&lt;
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
